<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming on Harsh&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.harshankur.com/categories/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming on Harsh&#39;s Blog</description>
    <image>
      <title>Harsh&#39;s Blog</title>
      <url>https://blog.harshankur.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://blog.harshankur.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 22:12:52 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.harshankur.com/categories/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using ChatGPT as an Assistant Developer</title>
      <link>https://blog.harshankur.com/posts/usingchatgptasanassistantdeveloper/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 22:12:52 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.harshankur.com/posts/usingchatgptasanassistantdeveloper/</guid>
      <description>When I first heard that AI will replace software developers soon, I thought it could not have been true as it is just a large language model as of now and not so much of an &amp;lsquo;intelligence&amp;rsquo; in any sense or form. Turns out, I was both right and wrong. It is trained well enough to support a developer but not to operate independently with simple instructions. So, it will take over a few people&amp;rsquo;s jobs, but that would be of the low-skilled software developers who only get to make a couple of small modules in the product at best.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Setup View Counter on Raspberry Pi Zero W</title>
      <link>https://blog.harshankur.com/posts/howisetupmyviewcounter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 12:02:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.harshankur.com/posts/howisetupmyviewcounter/</guid>
      <description>I like working on my own mini-projects in my free time. Some of them are libraries or extensions and others are websites. The libraries or extensions are distributed from their own package manager of browser web store which keep a track of all the downloads from across the world. It gets a little tricky for the websites if I do not want to inject a random script on my website that shows a hideously looking view counter from the 2000s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Curious Case of Undeclared Global Variables in Javascript</title>
      <link>https://blog.harshankur.com/posts/thecuriouscaseofundeclaredglobalvariablesinjavascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 16:43:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.harshankur.com/posts/thecuriouscaseofundeclaredglobalvariablesinjavascript/</guid>
      <description>How does your usual variable declaration look like? Like this, right?
const INTEREST_RATE = 20; // global const declaration and initialization var principleAmount; // global var declaration function calculateInterest() { principleAmount = 10000; // global var value assignment var timePeriod = 1; // local function scoped var declaration and initialization return principleAmount*INTEREST_RATE*timePeriod/100; } Do you know the difference between the above and below code snippet?
const INTEREST_RATE = 20; // global const declaration and initialization var principleAmount; // global var declaration function calculateInterest() { principleAmount = 10000; // global var value assignment timePeriod = 1; // &amp;lt;-- GLOBAL variable initialization without declaration return principleAmount*INTEREST_RATE*timePeriod/100; } Did you notice that var is missing behind timePeriod?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code on remote servers with Visual Studio Code via SSH</title>
      <link>https://blog.harshankur.com/posts/codeonremoteserversusingvisualstudiocodeviassh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 22:59:54 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.harshankur.com/posts/codeonremoteserversusingvisualstudiocodeviassh/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Have you ever struggled with debugging your code on remote servers? There are usually two issues associated with debugging on remote hosting.
You are not well versed with terminal-based editors like Vim and Nano
Coding locally, uploading to GitHub, downloading on remote server, and restarting servers with updating code is tiresome
Well, I have the perfect way for you! You can connect your Visual Studio Code application to your remote server directly via SSH.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
