<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Harsh&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.harshankur.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Harsh&#39;s Blog</description>
    <image>
      <title>Harsh&#39;s Blog</title>
      <url>https://blog.harshankur.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://blog.harshankur.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 23:36:34 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.harshankur.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How I use iOS Shortcuts</title>
      <link>https://blog.harshankur.com/posts/howiuseiosshortcuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 23:36:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.harshankur.com/posts/howiuseiosshortcuts/</guid>
      <description>What are iOS Shortcuts Shortcuts is a visual-scripting tool available on the Apple ecosystem which allows users to create macros for executing specific tasks on their device(s). These task sequences can be created by the user and shared online through iCloud. iOS Shortcuts can be a really powerful tool if it is used properly. It has some very advanced automation and scripting possibilities built into it and its best part is that it is available on a mobile device.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You can never go back home again</title>
      <link>https://blog.harshankur.com/posts/youcannevergobackhome/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 22:03:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.harshankur.com/posts/youcannevergobackhome/</guid>
      <description>This particular feeling hits home to me quite often. We live in an ever changing world where progressing time is the only constant. We are often consumed in our fast moving life and before we know it, we have moved far ahead without appreciating the good things that we once had.
I have never lived in one place for more than 5 years at a stretch except the place where I grew up, Kolkata, where I stayed for 6 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Setup View Counter on Raspberry Pi Zero W</title>
      <link>https://blog.harshankur.com/posts/howisetupmyviewcounter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 12:02:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.harshankur.com/posts/howisetupmyviewcounter/</guid>
      <description>I like working on my own mini-projects in my free time. Some of them are libraries or extensions and others are websites. The libraries or extensions are distributed from their own package manager of browser web store which keep a track of all the downloads from across the world. It gets a little tricky for the websites if I do not want to inject a random script on my website that shows a hideously looking view counter from the 2000s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Curious Case of Undeclared Global Variables in Javascript</title>
      <link>https://blog.harshankur.com/posts/thecuriouscaseofundeclaredglobalvariablesinjavascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 16:43:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.harshankur.com/posts/thecuriouscaseofundeclaredglobalvariablesinjavascript/</guid>
      <description>How does your usual variable declaration look like? Like this, right?
const INTEREST_RATE = 20; // global const declaration and initialization var principleAmount; // global var declaration function calculateInterest() { principleAmount = 10000; // global var value assignment var timePeriod = 1; // local function scoped var declaration and initialization return principleAmount*INTEREST_RATE*timePeriod/100; } Do you know the difference between the above and below code snippet?
const INTEREST_RATE = 20; // global const declaration and initialization var principleAmount; // global var declaration function calculateInterest() { principleAmount = 10000; // global var value assignment timePeriod = 1; // &amp;lt;-- GLOBAL variable initialization without declaration return principleAmount*INTEREST_RATE*timePeriod/100; } Did you notice that var is missing behind timePeriod?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code on remote servers with Visual Studio Code via SSH</title>
      <link>https://blog.harshankur.com/posts/codeonremoteserversusingvisualstudiocodeviassh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 22:59:54 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.harshankur.com/posts/codeonremoteserversusingvisualstudiocodeviassh/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Have you ever struggled with debugging your code on remote servers? There are usually two issues associated with debugging on remote hosting.
You are not well versed with terminal-based editors like Vim and Nano
Coding locally, uploading to GitHub, downloading on remote server, and restarting servers with updating code is tiresome
Well, I have the perfect way for you! You can connect your Visual Studio Code application to your remote server directly via SSH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up This Blog 💻</title>
      <link>https://blog.harshankur.com/posts/settingupthisblog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 23:22:50 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.harshankur.com/posts/settingupthisblog/</guid>
      <description>Setting up this blog has been long in the running. I wanted a minimal design with not a lot of flashy UI stuff. Further, I did not want an overly complicated blog system.
After a lot of investigation (and constantly saying NO to wordpress 😛), I landed upon Hugo to setup this blog. It was extremely easy to do it.
I found the documentation of Hugo quite resourceful and the online community is always at your fingertips.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction 🙏🏼</title>
      <link>https://blog.harshankur.com/posts/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 12:23:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.harshankur.com/posts/introduction/</guid>
      <description>I am happy to have finally set up this blog, which I had been intending to for the last few months. The primary objective for me in setting up this blog is to have a place of my own to dump my thoughts, my learnings, my experiences, and anything else I find useful to share with the world. I am aware that only a few people will ever discover this blog, but I am glad to finally have one that is not on social media.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
